this problem has
given us some data and asked us to
create a
hash that contains the data
and assign this hash to a variable named
car
before we begin to create a hash with
the data we've been given
let's first just look at the syntax of a
hash
hashes are made up of key value pairs
and we surround those key value pairs
with a pair of curly braces
when using a symbol as the key in your
hash
ruby allows us to use this very simple
and easy to read syntax
in this example number is the key
and one is its value in ruby versions
prior to 1.9
this same hash would be written like so
and you may hear this referred to as the
hashrocket syntax
now if we don't use symbols as the keys
in our hash
we still need to use this hashrocket
syntax
not only does using symbols as the keys
in our hash
allow us to use this new clean syntax
but symbols also take up less memory
than strings
now let's move on and write a hash for
the data that we were given in this
problem
we want to store a reference to this
hash in the local variable car
and looking at the table of data we were
given
we can see pretty clearly how we might
model this
data in a hash we will use
symbols as the keys in our hash
we know that our car has a type of sedan
is the color blue
and when i enter the mileage i'm going
to include an
underscore there that doesn't change the
value of this number
but it does make it more readable
now that we've written our hash
let's output it
hashes are a very commonly used data
structure
so make sure to get comfortable with the
required syntax